OPHIR BETSER

Highly motivated **Product Analyst** with a great passion for creating knowledge from data, in order to make the best decisions. Experienced in Statistical Analysis and Econometrics. skilled in **SQL**, **Python**, **R**, **Excel**, Visualization tools, and have great **self-learning ability**.

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

2022-01 | today

Google, Waze

Product Analytics

- Tel-Aviv. Israel
- Team-member of the Trips-DS team in Waze-Data-Guild and in Waze-Carpool-Squad
- Big-Data research and analysis on top of Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
- Working closely with product managers and developers on feature development, Experiments, user classification and monitoring key metrics.
- · Productization tables for the data warehouse.
- · Building dashboards and conducting in-depth research.
- A/B testing of new features

2021-01 | 2021-12

Ministry of Finance

Research Analyst

♀ Jerusalem, Israel

- Student in the Research-Team of 'Wage and Labor Agreements' Division.
- End-to-end analysis of the salaries and working conditions for +700K of Israel public sector workers.
- Extensive experience in R programming. Building automated analyses.
- · Writing research reports and creating complex visualizations.
- Publication of reports that have received public interest. (example).

2020-01 | 2020-12

Department of Economics

Research Assistant

Tel-Aviv, Israel

- Economometric research of crime data across the United States.
- Analysis of geographic data using Python.



ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2018 | 2021

B.A. in Economics

Tel Aviv University

Tel-Aviv, Israel

- Graduated Cum Laude.
- Extended **mathematics** studies.
- Excellence in Microeconomics and Econometrics studies.



TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2021 | today

Tel Aviv University

Teaching Assistant

- Tel-Aviv, Israel
- 2021: Economics in the Big Data World, Undergraduate Program.
- 2022: Economics in the Big Data World, Undergraduate Program. All course videos are in **Youtube**.
- 2022: Doing magic with Data, Kellogg-Recanati MBA Program.

2021 | today

Reichman University

Teaching Assistant

- Herzliah, Israel
- 2022: Data Science for Business, Mannheim & Reichman MBA Program.
- 2022: Data Analysis for Business Applications, AMBA Program.
- 2022: Exploratory Data Analysis, GMBA Program.
 All course videos are in Youtube.



REACH ME AT

J +972 53-420-9480

ophir.betser@gmail.com

github.com/ophirbetser
in linkedin.com/ophirbetser

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SQL

R

Data Visualization

Python

git

Airflow

Excel

Econometrics

Machine Learning

Web Scraping

HTML

CSS

SOFT SKILLS

Research

Teamwork

Problem-solving

Teaching

Presentation

Self-Learning Ability

Attention to details